<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Class &amp; Objects</title>
    <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Class &amp; Objects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 21:33:12 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Start Working Remotely?</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/getting_started_with_remote_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 21:33:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/getting_started_with_remote_work/</guid>
      <description>I first came across the notion of remote work when I was in college. I&amp;rsquo;m neither an extrovert not a complete introvert but somewhere in the middle. Right away I knew that remote work is for me and I want to do it. Even when I tried, it was not very easy to land a paid remote job. I had to do a full-time office for the first 20 months of my career and remote work clicked for me when I was going through the worst phase of my personal and professional life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Atom Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/the_perfect_atom_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 19:02:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/the_perfect_atom_setup/</guid>
      <description>I love my editor, Atom. I have tried most of them out there and still, I always come back to this one. It is not perfect but I find my peace in its imperfection. Here are few things I do to make my Atom awesome.
Making it beautiful I am a connoisseur when it comes to beauty. If you want me hooked, be beautiful. I love beautiful code and here is what I do to make my editor look beautiful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Quotes App on Android</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/best_quotes_app_android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 21:33:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/best_quotes_app_android/</guid>
      <description>If you are looking for motivation and inspiration, there is no other thing in the world like a Quote. Timeless words which will always mean something and bring out the best in you. Here are my listing for best quotes app on Android Play Store.
[Quoted: Quotes With Images] (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.classandobjects.quoted) This app lets you explore quotes and images. You can then easily save, share and use this images as wallpaper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level Up the Programming Skills : Language vs Logic</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/level_up_programming_skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 19:17:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/level_up_programming_skills/</guid>
      <description>Learning the language of computers can be both interesting and daunting. You may be either starting your career or are a seasoned developer, the chances are too likely that you are having trouble hitting the right balance between language and logical skills. In this article, I will try to find out what is the right balance to keep levelling up our programming skills.
In the current education system, most of the times, we tend to focus too much on the logical aspect of the programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Life: Work from home</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 23:11:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</guid>
      <description>I may be young, but age is just a number. I have seen life and work. I have been lost and I have been saved. I have travelled from the complete chaos of not knowing where to go and then to the bliss of understanding how everything fits together. I have hopped from language to language and now I understand them all(almost).
I love to code in Python, given how clean, readable and maintainable it looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hugo is best for blogging? You should use it too!</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/why_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 19:45:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/blogs/why_hugo/</guid>
      <description>Just like any blogger, I also wanted to start my own blog. I had many doubts. What is my niche? Will people read my blog? Which platform to use for blogging? I do not know if I have found my answers, but for the last one it is HUGO. Yes, I searched for different blogging platforms and all had their own set of drawbacks. Here are few reasons for not selecting them :</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
