<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>guide on Class &amp; Objects</title>
    <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/categories/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guide on Class &amp; Objects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 21:46:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.classandobjects.com/categories/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Way To Create Bottom Toolbar Like Google Plus Android App</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/create_google_plus_like_toolbar_android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 21:46:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/create_google_plus_like_toolbar_android/</guid>
      <description>Android toolbar is a neat functionality which replaces the old Actionbar. If you want to create a traditional looking, top positioned toolbar then this article is not for you. If you are looking for something in the line of Google plus bottom bar and have the ability to customize it then you should keep reading. Here are few screenshots to demonstrate what I mean.
The Layout Few thing to know before we start, I will not use menu options, it makes the toolbar creation easier but takes away the power to customize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Subscribe Button to Your Website, also Add a Scroll Triggered Subscribe Box</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/add_subscribe_button_on_static_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 22:35:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/add_subscribe_button_on_static_site/</guid>
      <description>Subscribe button is a useful feature to have on any website. It helps you create loyal audience base and helps your users get amazing content from the blogs they love. It can be quite easy to integrate one on a WordPress site or a website with a backend. In this article, I will show you how to add a subscribe button to any static website using formspree.io, Vex js and javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use React and MobX with Rails 5</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using_react_mobx_with_rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 01:02:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using_react_mobx_with_rails/</guid>
      <description>MobX is the new state management library which packs really well with react. Mobx makes things much simpler to redux, which is more famous in react community. I have detailed out the step on how to get started with using mobx and rails 5.
Install react_on_rails gem To make mobx functional with rails, I had to drop react-rails gem and adopt the react_on_rails gem. Setting it up is cumbersome in the beginning but it pays off well in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things Beginners Find Confusing About React.js</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/confusing_things_in_react/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 20:12:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/confusing_things_in_react/</guid>
      <description>React js is currently the most hyped front-end framework(view) today. I am lucky that at my current workplace I am getting a chance to explore react and rails. I am a Python lover, but I am completely open to learning new technologies. I have seen confusing things in Ruby on Rails which is very opposite to React and Javascript environment. I am trying to list out things every react js beginner should know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Easily Host a Static website on Github</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/host_static_site_on_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 15:36:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/host_static_site_on_github/</guid>
      <description>This post shows, how you can easily host your static website on Github. We are using Hugo static site generator. You can use anything similar.
Initial Setup I believe that you already have setup your hugo project, refer the link in case you want to start a project. Then open your config.toml file and modify the baseUrl as:
baseurl = &amp;quot;http://{username}.github.io/&amp;quot;
replace {username} with your username.
Repository for Project Files This step is not mandatory, but still you want to do this.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
