<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vue on Class &amp; Objects</title>
    <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/categories/vue/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vue on Class &amp; Objects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:59:20 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.classandobjects.com/categories/vue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Right Way to Use CSS Varialbes in Vue, Inspired by Tailwind.css</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using-css-variables-in-vue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 09:59:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using-css-variables-in-vue/</guid>
      <description>I can never emphasise enough on how Vue makes my life easy but I definitely want to work more in Vue if I&amp;rsquo;m doing frontend development. One issue that I face when building Vue applications using single file components(SFC) is about sharing the common style across components. There is no easy way to do this and most of you will be fine doing a copy paste of the styles across the components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Generator in Rails for Vue files</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/creating_a_rails_generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 10:58:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/creating_a_rails_generator/</guid>
      <description>When learning Rails we all learn about generators. I still remember when I saw it for the first time. I just fell in love with it. Writing a single command can create useful files and directories for me. Until recently I never had a chance to create a generator. Yesterday I did a blog on using Vue.js with Rails and I saw that I had to create a few files every time I wanted to add Vue to a view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Vue.js in Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using_vue_js_with_rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:58:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.classandobjects.com/tutorial/using_vue_js_with_rails/</guid>
      <description>Vue.js is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m telling this after having used React for more than a year in production software. I have written about my experience creating React SPA here. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried Vue yet, I highly recommend giving it a try. The developer experience is at the center. In this guide, we will see how to add Vue to a Rails project. So let&amp;rsquo;s get rolling.
In this post, we are going to migrate our devise signup page to use Vue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
